Asayake no kiri ni nijimu
朝焼けの霧に滲む
The mist of the morning glow spreads
La niebla del resplandor de la mañana se extiende
Sasayaku kanata no koe
囁く彼方の声
The voice of a distant whisper
La voz de un susurro lejano
Yume ga same tooku michiru
夢が覚め遠く満ちる
Waking up from a dream and rising in the distance
Despertarse de un sueño y levantarse en la distancia
Toki no otozure
時の訪れ
The arrival of time
La llegada del tiempo
Te ni ochita tsuyu ni utsuru
手に落ちた露に映る
The dew that fell on the hand reflects
El rocío que cayó sobre la mano refleja
Sonata no omokage
そなたの面影
Your face
Tu cara
Matedo izuko utsutsu ni
待てど　いずこ　うつつに
I waited (for a long time) for wherever reality
Esperé (durante mucho tiempo) donde sea que la realidad
Kokoro no oku de samayou
心の奥で　彷徨う
Wandering about inside of the heart
Deambulando por el interior del corazón
Hakanaku yureru
儚く揺れる
Swaying with mere hope
Balanceándose con mera esperanza
Nadeshiko sakura
なでしこ桜
Pink cherry blossoms
Flores de cerezo rosa
Ransei de umareta hana yo
乱世で生まれた花よ
Flowers that were born in troubled times
Flores que nacieron en tiempos difíciles
Akaku somerare
紅く染められ
Dyed red
Teñido de rojo
Ima, yomigaeru
今、よみがえる
Now I’m rising from the dead
Ahora me levanto de la muerte
Ano hi no nioi
あの日のにほひ
Engraved in that day
Grabado en ese día
Yoru ni hiraku hanabira
夜に開く花ビラ
The flower petals that open up at night
Los pétalos de flores que se abren por la noche
Oto mo naku tsudzuku michi o
音もなく　続く道を
Continuing down the soundless path
Continuando por el camino silencioso
Mamoru beki mono no tame
守るべき者のため
For the sake of protecting someone
Por el bien de proteger a alguien
Hitotoki no yami o terasu
ひとときの　闇を照らす
Illuminate the moment of darkness
Ilumina el momento de oscuridad
Tsuki kageboushi
月影ぼうし
The moonlight cover
La cubierta de luz de luna
Fukaki fuchi ni kasumeru
深き淵に霞める
Growing hazy in the deep abyss
Creciendo brumoso en el abismo profundo
Sonata no yubikiri
そなたの指切り
Your confirmation of a pinky promise
Su confirmación de una promesa de meñique
Shinobi yadoru kizuna to
忍び　宿る　絆と
With stealthy, dwelling emotional bonds
Con sigilosos lazos emocionales
Kokoro o tate ni tsuranuke
心を盾に貫け
The heart pierces through the shield
El corazón atraviesa el escudo
Adeyaka ni mau
艶やかに舞う
Fluttering about beautifully
Revoloteando maravillosamente
Nadeshiko sakura
なでしこ桜
Pink cherry blossoms
Flores de cerezo rosa
Ransei de kuchiteku hana yo
乱世で朽ちてく花よ
The flower that rots in troubled times
La flor que se pudre en tiempos difíciles
Kaze ni tawamure
風にたわむれ
Frolicking in the wind
Retozando en el viento
Ima, shidare yuku
今、枝垂(しだ)れゆく
Now, drooping down
Ahora, cayendo
Kasukana nioi
微(かす)かなにほひ
Faintly engraved
Levemente grabado
Iro wa utsuri ni keri na
色は移りにけりな
The color changes from the past to the present
El color cambia del pasado al presente
Ima hitotsu mata hitotsu kobore yuku
今ひとつ　またひとつ　零れゆく
One more and then another, peeking through
Uno más y luego otro, mirando a través de
Hana umi ni uzumorete
花海に　うずもれて
Hidden in a sea of flowers
Escondido en un mar de flores
Towa ni meguri meguru yumemigusa
永遠に巡り巡る夢見草
Cherry blossom petals rotating in a swirl for eternity
Pétalos de flor de cerezo girando en un remolino para la eternidad
Hakanaku yureru
儚く揺れる
Swaying with mere hope
Balanceándose con mera esperanza
Nadeshiko sakura
なでしこ桜
Pink cherry blossoms
Flores de cerezo rosa
Ransei de umareta hana yo
乱世で生まれた花よ
Flowers that were born in troubled times
Flores que nacieron en tiempos difíciles
Akaku somerare
紅く染められ
Dyed red
Teñido de rojo
Ima, yomigaeru
今、よみがえる
Now, I'm rising from the dead
Ahora me levanto de la muerte
Ano hi no nioi
あの日のにほひ
Engraved in that day
Grabado en ese día
Yoru ni hiraku hanabira
夜に開く花ビラ
The flower petals that open up at night
Los pétalos de flores que se abren por la noche
Wasureru koto nakare
忘れることなかれ
We must not forget
No debemos olvidar